<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>Thought Machine</title>
 <link href="http://thoughtmachine.co//" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://thoughtmachine.co/"/>
 <updated>2013-03-07T23:58:28-05:00</updated>
 <id>http://thoughtmachine.co/</id>
 <author>
   <name>Thought Machine</name>
   <email>blah@email.test</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Hello World.</title>
   <link href="http://thoughtmachine.co//hello-world"/>
   <updated>2013-03-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://thoughtmachine.co//hello-world</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hi. Welcome to Thought Machine. Thanks for reading. Have a soda.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started this blog because we were kind of annoyed. Dan and I would get drinks every so often, and our conversations would inevitably turn to the state of programming. It was amazing that, in the past couple of years, a number of things about making programs have become substantially more awesome: frameworks like Ruby on Rails, libraries like jQuery, and platforms like Amazon Web Services have made the process of creating websites more accessible and less annoying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, despite the dramatic improvements being made in the world of libraries and frameworks, one thing remained frustratingly stagnant: &lt;strong&gt;the tools we use to make programs themselves&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we would get drinks and talk about this stuff and we would end the night pounding our fists on the table. And we figured that other people must be as annoyed about this as we were.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We looked around the Internet, and we found some promising signs. There are definitely some really amazing people (in both academia and industry) doing very interesting work around making better programming tools. And the really cool thing is that some of the most exceptional thinking on this topic was done decades ago, and is only coming into mainstream acceptance now. So it&amp;#8217;s a cool time to be thinking about this stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more disquieting flip side to to that, though, is how many people are &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; upset about the way we make programs. There seems to be a strong sentiment that we reached perfection decades ago with vim, emacs, and bash, and any attempt to improve is a fool&amp;#8217;s errand. This might be true. But we&amp;#8217;re fools, and we need an errand, so this one may as well be ours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope, then, that this blog might serve two purposes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We&amp;#8217;d like to document the projects, historical and contemporary, that aspire to make the act of creating programs easier, less error-prone, faster, and more fun.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;We&amp;#8217;d also like to offer some thoughts on how the act of creating programs might be improved, even if our ideas have yet to be realized in any meaningful way. Basically, we want to get you fired up about the possibility of a better future with regards to program creation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#8217;s it. We hope you enjoy. Maybe you&amp;#8217;ll even get inspired to take your own strides towards improving the program-making process. Or maybe you&amp;#8217;ll send us hate mail when we diss Smalltalk or whatever. Either way, we&amp;#8217;ll keep pounding our fists on the metaphorical table, and maybe when we&amp;#8217;re old and grizzled, programming computers will look like a very different task indeed.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>